Morwarid Najafizada

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data Analyst with three years of experience working as a Data Analyst. Strong problem-solving, analyzing, and researching skills. Experienced in modeling, interpreting, and reporting data. Recognized for maximizing performance by implementing and managing appropriate project analysis.

EXPERIENCE

Data Performance Analyst, StorageVault Canada Inc

Sep 2018 – Present

- Successfully interpreted data to draw conclusions for managerial action and strategy.
- Designed and interpreted key performance indicators and analytical models driving channel strategy and productivity.
- Build and maintained performance models and reports as well as communicated the results and recommendations to the leadership team.
- Created static and ad-hoc deliverables to communicate performance and increased efficiency.
- Designed, coded, tested, maintained, and documented dashboard visualizations.

Data Entry Clerk, UN Association in Canada

June 2015 – Sep 2018

- Expanded the portfolio of sponsors by tracking and processing monthly changes and troubleshooting in the database.
- Generated regular reports and data exports, including tax receipts, gift acknowledgments, and membership lists.
- Processed contact and gift donation into Raiser's Edge a fundraising and constituent relationship management (CRM) system and saved the department 30 hours of manual work each week.
- Grew 20+ sponsors and donors by assisting with research.

PROJECTS

COVID-19 in the US Descriptive Analysis, CareerFoundry

Feb 2021

- Conducted an ad-hoc descriptive analysis of US COVID-19 metadata.
- Build a Linear Regression model to predict the number of deaths in the upcoming season and presented the results in dashboards and Excel reports.

Instacart Grocery Basket Exploratory Analysis, CareerFoundry

Dec 202

- Performed exploratory analysis of the historical data of customers to derive insights and suggest strategies to better segmentation.
- Wrangled, aggregated, and merged the datasets to achieve better results and generated the results in reports and dashboards to communicate insights to stakeholders.

Rockbuster Stealth Data Analysis Project, CareerFoundry

Sep 2020

- Performed an ETL process and extract data from multiple sources.
- Answered any ad-hoc business questions the management board had.
- Presented the SQL results to the business manager by creating compelling dashboard stories and reports.

US Flu Predictive Analysis, CareerFoundry

June 2020

- Provided information to support a staffing plan using Pivot Table.
- Presented the conclusions, recommendations, and proposed next steps in final presentations and reports.

Ontario, Canada

+1 (613) 698 – 7059

morwarid1.github.io/ github.com/morwarid1

 $\underline{morwarid.naja fizada@gmail.com}$

linkedin.com/in/morwarid

public.tableau.com/app/profile/mor warid.najafizada

SKILLS

- SOL
- Python (Pandas, Geopandas, Numpy, Sci-Kit, Matplotlib, Seaborn)
- Interactive dashboards
- Tableau dashboards
- Power BI reports
- Data Analytics
- Data Modeling
- Data Transformation
- Data Visualizations
- MS Excel
- Business Requirements
- Hypothesis testing
- Machine Learning
- Linear Regression Analysis
- Data quality & integrity checks
- Data mining and wrangling

EDUCATION

Data Immersion Certificate

CareerFoundry

Feb 2021

 Storytelling, SQL, Python, Data Ethics, Advanced Analytics, and Dashboard Design.

Bachelor of Business Analytics

University of Ottawa

Sep 2018 - May 2021

 Business Simulation Analytics, Business Forecasting Analytics, Business Optimization Analytics, Application of Business Analytics.

Data Analytics Certificate

CareerFoundry

June 2020

 Hypothesis & Statistical Analysis, Data Wrangling.